Byron Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Byron Gallery records
circa 1950s-1991
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Byron Gallery
16.3 linear feet
The records of New York Byron Gallery measure 16.3 linear feet and date from circa 1950s-1991, with the bulk of the material dating from 1960-1971. The records document the gallery's representation and exhibition of Surrealist and contemporary American artists, as well as the occasional pre-Columbian and Old Masters artwork. Found are over ten linear feet of artists and subject files, fifty-seven exhibition scrapbooks, exhibition catalogs, and sales records. There are also exhibitions catalogs of the Milan Galleria Dell'Arieti.
Provenance
The Byron Gallery papers were donated to the Archives of American Art by gallery owner Charles Byron in 1999.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
The Byron Gallery was founded in 1961 by Charles Byron (b. 1918) and located on Madison Avenue in New York, New York. The gallery primarily showed Surrealist masters and up-and-coming contemporary American painters and sculptures, as well as an occasional ancient and Old Masters exhibit.
Among the artists represented by the gallery were Alcopley, Herbert Bayer, Albert Kotin, Clement Meadmore, Richard Merkin, Constantino Nivola, Brian O'Doherty, and Hans Richter. Additional artists handled by the gallery or given shows were Max Ernst, Sam Gilliam, Robert Sebastian Matta, Renee Magritte, Sylvia Sleigh, and Jack Youngerman. The gallery also sold work by artists represented by other galleries, or from the secondary market.
Several prescient group shows were organized by the gallery, including the Box Show in 1965, featuring the work of over 100 artists, including Arakawa, Lee Bontecou, Chryssa, Joseph Cornell, Alcopley, Walter De Maria, Dan Flavin, Donald Judd, Edward Kienholz, Sol Lewitt, Louise Nevelson, Constantino Nivola, Robert Rauschenberg, Michell Stuart, and Andy Warhol. The Paris Review show in 1965 was another stellar event, with contributions from Richard Anuszkiewicz, Allan D'Arcangelo, Jim Dine, Helen Frankenthaler, Robert Indiana, Alex Katz, Ellsworth Kelly, Lindner, Richard Robert Motherwell, Louise Nevelson, Estaban Vicente, and Andy Warhol. In 1964, the gallery also organized an exhibition of over 40 American landscape artists, American Landscapes. The gallery also exhibited two shows based on Pre-Columbian objects, and, in the late 1960s, held two major exhibitions, 400 Years of Italian Art: Florentine Relief Fund Art Show (1967) and Greek Gold Exhibition (1967-1968).
Scope and Content Note
The records of New York Byron Gallery measure 16.3 linear feet and date from circa 1950s-1991, with the bulk of the material dating from 1960-1971. The records document the gallery's representation and exhibition of Surrealist and contemporary American artists, as well as the occasional pre-Columbian and Old Masters artwork. Found are extensive artists and subject files, exhibition files and scrapbooks, exhibition catalogs, and sales records. There are also exhibitions catalogs of the Milan Galleria Dell'Arieti.
Artist and subject files comprise over one-half of the records and contain business correspondence, sales information, photographs and transparencies, catalogs, and exhibit reviews for each artist either represented or sold by the gallery, or participated in an exhibition organized by the gallery. Particularly rich files are found for Alcopley, Stephen Antonakos, Alexander Calder, Pietro Consagra, Giorgio De Chirico, Max Ernst, Pedro Friedeberg, Sam Gilliam, Mathias Goeritz, Sarah Grilo, Roberto Sabastiano Matta, Clement Meadmore, Constantino Nivola, Sylvia Sleigh, Paul Talman, and Jack Youngerman.
Fifty-seven exhibition scrapbooks in binder sleeves represent a complete documentary record of Byron Gallery exhibits from 1963-1970. The scrapbook contain a wide variety of materials, including correspondence, catalogs, price lists, installation photographs and slides, printed reproductions of exhibited art work, and newspaper clippings and reviews. Additional printed materials include exhibition catalogs and invitations. There is also a near-complete run of catalogs from the Galleria Dell'Arieti, a contemporary gallery in Milan, Italy, 1961-1970.
Financial and business records are contained in a series of invoices from 1963-1971, and a card file of artwork sold or returned.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 5 series:
Series 1: Artist and Subject Files, circa 1950s-1991, undated (Box 1-10, 17; 10.2 linear feet)
Series 2: Exhibition Scrapbooks, 1963-1970 (Box 11-14, 17; 4.1 linear feet)
Series 3: Printed Material, 1961-1970 (Box 15; 0.5 linear foot)
Series 4: Invoices, 1963-1971 (Box 15; 0.5 linear foot)
Series 5: Card Files, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 16; 1 linear foot)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Copley, Alfred L.; Antonakos, Stephen,1926-; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976; Consagra, Pietro, 1920-; De Chirico, Giorgio, 1888-; Ernst, Max, 1891-1976; Friedeberg, Pedro, 1937-; Gilliam, Sam; Goeritz, Mathias,$d1915-; Grilo, Sarah; Matta Echaurren, Roberto Sebastián, 1911-; Meadmore, Clement; Nivola, Costantino, 1911-; Sleigh, Sylvia; Talman, Paul; Youngerman, Jack, 1926-; Galleria dell'Ariete
Subjects-Topical:
Art galleries, Commercial -- New York (State)-- New York; Surrealism
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Scrapbooks
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Artist/Subject Files, circa 1950s-1991, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1-10, 17; 10.2 linear feet)
  Artist and subject files contain business correspondence, sales information, photographs and transparencies, catalogs, and exhibit reviews for each artist either represented or sold by the gallery, or whom participated in an exhibition organized by the gallery. Particularly rich files are found for Alcopley, Stephen Antonakos, Alexander Calder, Pietro Consagra, Giorgio De Chirico, Max Ernst, Pedro Friedeberg, Sam Gilliam, Mathias Goeritz, Sarah Grilo, Roberto Sabastiano Matta, Clement Meadmore, Constantino Nivola, Sylvia Sleigh, Paul Talman, and Jack Youngerman.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the artist's last name or by subject (most often titles of exhibitions).
  - Artists "A" Miscellaneous, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Akyavas, Erol, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albers, Josef, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alcopley, L., circa 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alcopley, L., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Drawings Show (1964), 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Andrews, Stephen, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Antonakos, Stephen, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Antonakos, Stephen, 1964-1970, (Oversized material housed in Box 17, F1) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Architects Drawings, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arp, Jean, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Artists Represented, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Artists Statements, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Artists to be Considered, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ashbee, Helen, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Assorted Artists, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Avery, Milton, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Artists "B" Miscellaneous, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bacon, Francis, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Balkin, Stephen, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Balla, Giacomo, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Balthus, 1977-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bardazzi, Peter, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Barker, Walter, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Basen, Dan, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bastin, Michele, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Baugniet, Marcel Louis, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bauhaus, Robert and Ella Bergmann, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bayer, Herbert, circa 1960s-1970s, (3 folders; Oversized material housed in Box 17, F2) (Box 1, Folder 29-31)
  - Bayrak, Tosun, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Beaton, Cecil, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bellmer, Hans, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Benson, Ben, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Biegas, Boleslas, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Boghosian, Varujan, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Boissier, J.J., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bolles, Robert, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bonnard, Pierre, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Botero, Fernando, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Botero, Fernando, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bouchant, Andre, 1985, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Box Show Artists (1968), 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brasley, S., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brauner, Victor, circa 1960s-1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brauner, Victor, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brauner, Victor, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Brown, Judith, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bruce, Patrick Henry, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Brüning, Peter, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Butchkes, Sydney, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Artists "C" Miscellaneous, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Calder, Alexander, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Calder, Alexander, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cardenas, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Carrington, Leonora, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Carrington, Leonora, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Carter, Clarence, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cascella, Andrea, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Cassatt, Mary, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Catlin, George, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Cesar, Nadine, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Cezanne, Paul, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Chabrol, Baron de, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Chagall, Marc, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Chalem, Celine, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Chase, Ronald, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Chattaway, William, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Chinn Yuen, Yuey, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Christo, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Clergue, Lucien, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Consagra, Pietro, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Consagra, Pietro, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Consignment: Returned to Artist, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Copley, William, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Copley, William, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Corbassiere, Yves, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Corbero, Xavier, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Corbero, Xavier, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Cordier-Ekstrom Gallery, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Cornell, Joseph, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Costa Rica, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Crotti, Jean, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Cuartas, Gregorio, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Artists "D" Miscellaneous, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Dado, circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Dado, circa 1960s-1970 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Dallos, Miklos, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Daumier, H., undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Dechar, Peter, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - De Chirico, Giorgio, 1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - De Chirico, Giorgio, 1970-1991 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Delacroix, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - De Sanctis, Fabio, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dominguez, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Douihny, Saliba, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dubuffet, Jean, 1968-1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Duchamp, Marcel, circa 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Duvillier, Rene, circa 1960s, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 7-9)
  - Artists "E" Miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Edelheit, Martha, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Edelheit, Martha, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Edlich, Stephen, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Eleu, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ensor, James, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ernst, Max, 1977-1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Ernst, Max, Dallas, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ernst, Max Exhibition (1970), 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Ernst, Max, Oils, undated, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 19-22)
  - Ernst, Max Sculpture (October-December 1990), 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Ernst, Max Sculpture Project (1990-91), 1984-1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Esqueda, Xavier, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - European and South American Countries, circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - European Countries, 1960-1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Artists "F" Miscellaneous, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fernandel, Augustin, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fini, Leonore, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Finklestein, Michael, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Finn, Gloria, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fitzia, (Mendialdua), 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Flavin, Daniel, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Florentine Relief Fund Art Show (1967), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Floris, Marcel, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fontana, L., 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 400 Years of Italian Art Exhibition, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 400 Years of Italian Art Exhibition Insurance, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Francis, Sam, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Frank, Mary, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Frankenthaler, Helen, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Freeman, John, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "French" (Several Artists), undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Fried, Otto, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro (1964), 1964 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro, 1964-1970, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro: Correspondence, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Friedeberg, Pedro: Loans, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Fuchs, Ernst, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Fuhrman, Charles, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Fukuda, Shigeo, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Fuseli, Henry, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Artists "G" Miscellaneous, 1963-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Galleria della' Arieta, 1968-1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Gallery Chauvelin, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Gauguin, Paul, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Geofroy, Henry de, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Giacometti, Alberto, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Giles, William, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Gilliam, Sam, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Gilliam, Sam, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Gnoli, Domenico, 1967-1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Goeritz, Mathias, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Goeritz, Mathias, 1963-1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Goeritz, Mathias, 1963-1971, (Oversized material housed in Box 17, F3) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Gottleib, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Gray, Cleve, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Grebenak, Louis, 1964-1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Greenly, Colin, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Grilo, Sarah, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Grilo, Sarah, 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Gris, Juan, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Group Show, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Gutman, Willi, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Artists "H" Miscellaneous, 1964-1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Haglund, Birber, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Hair, Bryce, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Halbig, Johann von, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Hebner, E.F., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Helleu, Paul, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Henry, Robert, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Hepworth, Barbara, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Hirst, Barry, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Hockney, David, 1965-1976 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Hogle, Richard, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Houdon, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Hubler, Rudolf, 1964-1970 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Hughes, Ralph, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Hutchinson, Peter, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Artists "I" Miscellaneous, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Indian Art, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Isham, Sheila, 1964-1971 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Italy, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Artists "J" Miscellaneous, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Janson, Marc, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Jean, Marcel, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Johns, Jasper, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Artists "K" Miscellaneous, 1963-1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Kandinsky, Wassily, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Kauffman, Angelica, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Klee, Paul, 1968-1982, (Oversized material housed in Box 17, F4) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Klimt, Gustave, circa 1980s-1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Knoop, Guitou, 1962-1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Koplin, Norma Jean, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Kotin, Albert, 1964-1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Kotin, Albert, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Krebs, Rockne, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lam, Wilfreda, circa 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Landscapes, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Leger, Fernand, 1968-1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Lichtenstein, Roy, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Liikala, Bob, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Lindner, Richard, 1953-1973 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Lockeckts, Barbara, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Louis, Morris, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Artists "M" Miscellaneous, 1963-1970 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Magritte, Rene, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Mari, Enzo, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Marotta, Gino, 1965-1968 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Masson, Andre, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Matisse, Henri, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Matta, Roberto Sabastiano, 1968-1981 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Matta, Roberto Sabastiano (1970), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - McDowell, Barrie, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - McEwen, Rory, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - McEwen, Rory, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Meadmore, Clement, 1966-1970 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Meadmore, Clement, 1968-1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Meadmore, Clement - Sculptures, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Meadmore, Clement - Sculptures, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Melotti, Fausto, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Merkin, Richard, 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Michaux, Henri, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Micossi, Mario, 1963-19641963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Milby, David, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Milian, Raul, 1960-19661960-1966 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Millington-Drake, Teddy, 1968-1971 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Millington-Drake, Teddy, 1972-1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Miro, Joan, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Modern Sculpture Show (1968), 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Modigliani, Amadeo, 1970-1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Mondrian, Piet, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Monumental Sculpture Projects, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Moore, Henry, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Morisot, Berthe, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Motherwell, Robert, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Muro, Fernandez, 1962-1970 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Artists "N" Miscellaneous, 1964-1970 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Nadelman, Elie, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Nevelson, Louise, 1957-1969 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Nivola, Constantino, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Nivola, Constantino, 1963-1967 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Nivola, Constantino, 1963-1971 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Nivola, Constantino, 1963-1990 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Nivola, Constantino, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Nivola, Constantino, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Noel, George, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Noguchi, Isamu, 1966-1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Noland, Kenneth, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Artists "O" Miscellaneous, 1964-1971 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - O'Doherty, Brian, 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Ossorio, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Artists "P" Miscellaneous, 1963-1970 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Paalen, Wolfgang, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Paris Master, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Paris Review Show (1965), 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Patrikiades, George-Greek Gold Exhibition, 1964-1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Patrikiades, George-Greek Gold Exhibition, Consignments, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Patrikiades, George-Greek Gold Exhibition, Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Patrikiades, George-Greek Gold Exhibition, Customs, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Peire, Luc, 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Pelaez, Antonio, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Peverelli, Cesare, 1957-1969 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Pfriem, Bernard, 1963-1967 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Picabia, Francis, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Picasso, Pablo, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1980-1988 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Pilot Galleries (Lausanne), 1966 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Pissarro, Camille, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Pistoletto, Michelangelo, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Plumm, W., undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Pohl, Uli, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Pollock, Jackson, circa 1970s-1982 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Ponc, J., 1970 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Poons, Larry, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Porter, Fairfield, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Pre-Columbian, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Pre-Columbian, 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Pre-Columbian-Negatives, circa 1960s (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Protest Posters, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Pye, William, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Artists "R" Miscellaneous, 1962-1971 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Rabkin, Leo, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Ralston, Glen, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Ray, Man, 1976-1982 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Rayo, Omar, 1966-1968 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Renard, Fernand, 1963-1968 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Renoir, Claude, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Renoir, Pierre-Auguste, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Richter, Hans, 1963-1969 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Richter, Hans, 1965-1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rivera, Diego, circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Rivers, Larry, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rood, John, 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Rosofsky, Seymour, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Rothko, Mark, 1973-1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Rougement, Guy de, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Rubenstein, Lewis, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Rudge, John, 1965-1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Rudge, John, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Artists "S" Miscellaneous, 1963-1970 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Sage, Kay, 1985, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Sakier, George, 1963-1967 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Sander, Ludwig, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Schoeffer, Nicholas, 1966-1969 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Schueler, Jon, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Schwedler, William, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Schwitters, Kurt, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Seligman, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Sequin, Olivier, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Serego, John, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Shields, Alan, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Silva, Alvaro de, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Simeti, Tuzi, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Sisley, Alfred, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Sleigh, Sylvia, 1964-1968 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Sleigh, Sylvia, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Small, Neal, 1968-1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Smith, David, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Smith, R., 1972 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Sonenberg, Jack, 1962-1971 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Spaeth, Sigrid, 1964-1967 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Springer, Ferdinand, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Spyropoulos, Jannis, 1965-1971 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Staff, Donald, 1968-1971 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Steinberg, Saul, undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Stella, Frank, 1960-1981 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Stern, Gerd, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Still, Clifford, undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Stokes, Thomas P., circa 1975 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Artists "T" Miscellaneous, 1962-1968 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Talman, Paul, 1960-1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Talman, Paul, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Talman, Paul, 1965-1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Tanguy, Yves, 1973, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Tanguy, Yves, 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Tellesch, Gotha, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Tinguely, Jean, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Tobey, Mark, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Toledo, Francisco, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Townsend, John, 1965-1968 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Toyen, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)